

Timothy D. Cook
Chief Executive Officer and
Director
Apple Inc.



White / Caucasian

ETHNICITY

AGE	63
GENDER	M
PUBLIC BOARDS	2

# $\mathbb{X}$

# Experience

# Apple Inc.

Chief Executive Officer and Director August 2011 - Present

### **Former Executive Positions**

Chief Operating Officer

N/A - August 2011

Executive Vice President, Worldwide Sales and Operations

Senior Vice President, Worldwide Operations, Sales, Service & Support

Senior Vice President, Worldwide Operations

#### **Board Member**

August 2011 - Present

98.33% approval (as of 02/28/2024)

# NIKE, Inc.

#### **Board Member**

November 2005 - Present

Lead Director

Compensation Committee Chair 98.1% approval (as of 09/10/2024)

# **Former Board Positions**

Compensation Committee Member

Nominating and Corporate Governance Committee Member

### Business Roundtable

**Board Member** 

Duke University

**Board Member** 

The Oxford Foundry, University of Oxford

Founder

Robert F. Kennedy Center for Justice & Human Rights

Former Board Member

April 2016 - N/A

# **Biography**

Mr. Cook, 63, a director since 2005, is the Company's Lead Independent Director and the Chief Executive Officer of Apple, Inc. ("Apple"). As CEO, Mr. Cook leads Apple's work to create and share technology that empowers people and enriches their lives.

- Mr. Cook joined Apple in March 1998 as Senior Vice President of Worldwide Operations and also served as its Executive Vice President, Worldwide Sales and Operations and Chief Operating Officer.
- Mr. Cook was Vice President, Corporate Materials for Compaq Computer Corporation from 1997 to 1998.
- Previous to his work at Compaq, Mr. Cook served in the positions of Senior Vice President Fulfillment and Chief Operating Officer of the Reseller Division at Intelligent Electronics from 1994 to 1997.
- Mr. Cook earned an MBA from Duke University, where he was a Fuqua Scholar, and a Bachelor of Science degree in Industrial Engineering from Auburn University.

Mr. Cook is a member of the Board of Directors of Apple. In addition to this public company board service, he is also a member of the Board of Directors of the National Football Foundation and Duke University Board of Trustees. Mr. Cook is a consistent advocate for civil rights, the fundamental right to privacy, and equitable access to education, while also leading Apple's work to become 100% carbon neutral by 2030.

Continue on page 2



Learn more at

## Compaq

#### Former Executive Position

VP, Corporate Materials 1997 - 1998

### Intelligent Electronics

#### **Former Executive Position**

Senior Vice President Fulfillment & Chief Operating Officer of the Reseller Division 1994 - 1997

#### IBM

#### Former Executive Position

Director, North American Fulfillment 1983 - 1994

## Education

Duke University

M.B.A. 1988

Auburn University

B.S. 1982

## Skills

VC/PE Backed Company

Compensation Committee (Chair)

Photo Source

http://allthingsd.com/files/2012/04/Tim-cook.jpg on Sep-12-2024

# **Updates**



Lead Independent Director at NIKE, Inc.

Former: Board Member

Jul 1, 2016 (SEC) | Jun 30, 2016 (Effective)



Chief Executive Officer and Director at Apple Inc.

Former: Chief Operating Officer

Aug 26, 2011 (SEC) | Aug 24, 2011 (Effective)



Board Member at NIKE, Inc.

Aug 9, 2006 (SEC) | Nov 17, 2005 (Effective)

# **Equity Transactions**



EQUITY HOLDINGS	\$800.8	М
ANNUAL COMPENSATION *	\$63.6	М

<sup>\*</sup> Based on publicly-disclosed data. May include director fees.

Equilar ExecAtlas<sup>TM</sup> is a state of the art prospect research solution to grow your business. Identify meaningful business relationships and reach high potential prospects through the power of your network. Learn more at equilar.com/executive-network



Learn more at